Friend: What was your best ever New Year’s Eve?
One you always remember?
Denisa: Oh, definitely 2014, when I was in Rio.
Friend: Who were you with?
Denisa: I was with my boyfriend Marcelo, who’s Brazilian.
Friend: Why was it so special?
Denisa: Well, Brazil has special traditions for New Year’s Eve, and they were all new for me.
For example, it’s a Brazilian tradition to wear white clothes for New Year’s Eve
because white is a symbol of peace,
so I wore a beautiful white dress that Marcelo’s mother bought me.
I have a photo somewhere on my phone.
Yes, here, look!
Friend: How pretty. So, what did you do?
Denisa: Uh, let me think.
Well, first we had a typical New Year’s Eve dinner with Marcelo’s family.
And then, I guess it was about ten, we got a bus to Copacabana.
Friend: What was the atmosphere like there?
Denisa: Oh, it was amazing! The streets were already full of people.
We went to a show at a place near the beach. It was great, and we danced the samba.
Friend: Wow. Were you there at midnight?
Denisa: No, no. When we saw it was almost midnight,
we went to the beach, and the typical countdown started,
you know – ten, nine, eight…Happy New Year!
Everywhere we heard the sound of people celebrating,
and we watched the wonderful fireworks.
Friend: It sounds great. What did people do when the fireworks finished?
Denisa: Most people went to other parties, or they went home.
Friend: And what about you?
Denisa: We decided to go to a different beach,
a beach called Praia do Arpoador, and we took our first swim of the new year.
It was magical.